[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这是我们的生命意义运行示例，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Here's our meaning of life running example,
写得更清楚一点来证明这一点关于提问。
written a little bit more clearly to prove this point about asking questions.
看第6行。
Look at line 6.
我说x等于1+，然后我进行Ajax调用。
I say x is equal to 1 + and then I make an AJAX call.
我在Ajax调用结束时让步，好吧。
And I yield while the AJAX call is finishing, okay.
Ajax调用getData立即不返回任何内容。
That AJAX call, getData, returns me nothing right away.
但你会注意到，在它运行后的1000毫秒，在第二行，
But you'll notice that 1,000 milliseconds after it runs, up on line two,
我们在二号线上打什么电话？
what do we call up on line two?
我们调用run来重新启动，用我们返回的值恢复生成器。
We call run to restart, to resume the generator with the value that we got back.
因此，在1000毫秒之后，我们的伪Ajax给出了来自Ajax调用的响应。
So after 1000 milliseconds, our fake AJAX gives us the response from our AJAX call.
那么这个价值又从何而来呢？
And where does that value come back?
回到第6行的屈服表达式。
Right back to the yield expression on line 6.
所以我们马上得到值10。
So we get the value 10 right back.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：所以我们这里有同步看起来异步的代码。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So what we have here is synchronous looking asynchronous code.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：我们能够在我们的生成器内部本地阻止作为
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: We are able to block locally inside of our generator as
如果有什么神奇的暂停简历的事情。
if there is some magical pause resume thing.
因为现在有一个暂停简历，它是生成器。
Because there is a pause resume now, and it's the generator.
发电机的管道可以暂停，等待
The plumbing of the generator is able to pause, wait for
还有其他的背景工作要完成。
some other background thing to finish.
然后继续使用我们等待的值。
And then resume with the value that we were waiting for.
所以在我们的生成器中，从第六行到第十一行，这就是我们的程序逻辑。
So inside of our generator, line six through eleven, that's our program logic.
这就是我们一遍又一遍写的东西。
That's the stuff we write over and over and over again.
一线到三线和十五线，
Lines one through three and line fifteen,
这些都是隐藏在某个图书馆里的管道。
that's all plumbing that gets hidden away in some library somewhere.
我们的程序逻辑，我们的流量控制看起来像6到11。
Our program logic, our flow control looks like 6 through 11.
现在，如果你在脑海中想象与二十张幻灯片相比，或者
Now, if you mentally picture that compared to twenty slides ago or
不管怎样，当我们越过承诺链的时候。
whatever, when we went over the promise chain.
承诺链是流控制的一种形式，最终
Promise chains are a form of flow control that ends up
将一串函数调用垂直定向到一个承诺链中。
vertically orienting a bunch of function calls into a promise chain.
如果你再回想一下，我们有Thunks，它们被嵌套在一起，
And if you think even further back, we had thunks and they were nested together and
回电，他们都有那种怪异。
callbacks, they had all that kind of weirdness.
所以这里我们又有了流量控制。
So here we have flow control again.
但是这种特殊的流控制的神奇之处在于它看起来是同步的。
But what's so magic about this particular flow control is that it looks synchronous.
为什么这很重要？
Why is that so important?
因为这是我们大脑的工作方式。
Because that's the way our brains work.
我们不需要任何开销，那些传球的样板
We don't have to have any of that overhead, that boilerplate of passing
将事物作为回调和链接事物并返回。
things in as callbacks and chaining things and returning.
所有这些东西都会被隐藏起来，这是一个实现细节。
All that stuff gets hidden away, it's an implementation detail.
我们所做的就是将异步性本身
What we've done is taking asynchronicity itself and
将其作为我们不关心的实现细节进行分解。
factored it out as an implementation detail that we do not care about.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：我不确定我刚才所说的全部重量是
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: I'm not really sure that the full weight of what I just said is
真的过来了。
actually coming across.
这可是件大事。
That's a huge deal.
取异步性本身并将其分解为
Taking asynchronicity itself and factoring it out so
我们不必担心。
that we don't have to worry about it.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：我们编写同步的、顺序的、看起来像块的代码。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: We write synchronous, sequential, blocking looking code.
我们让图书馆处理所有丑陋的部分。
And we let the library handle all of the ugly bits.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 2：是否获得与getData相同的性能，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Does it get the same performance like if it the getData,
如果不是打外线电话，
if it's not making an external call,
它本身就是一个函数，它正在进行一些巨大的操作？
it's a function in itself and it's making some huge operation?
它会得到相同的性能，就像我与web worker或
Will it get the same performance like if I do with a web worker or
一些事情，我必须做一个异步-。
something where I have to do an asynchronous-.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：不，不要把这个和线程混淆，好吗？
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: No, no, no, no, no, don't get this confused with threads, okay.
如果行为发生在JavaScript程序中，
If the behavior is happening in your JavaScript program,
它占用了单个事件线程。
it is taking up the single event thread.
这与向网络工作者发送消息不是一回事。
This is not the same thing as messaging out to a web worker.
你能给二号线的网络工作者发信息吗？
Could you message out to a web worker on line two?
绝对的。
Absolutely.
但是第2行不会因为你调用它而神奇地变成一个网络工作者
But line 2 doesn't magically become like a web worker just because you called it
来自发电机。
from a generator.
我们的JavaScript程序仍然只有一个线程可以运行。
There's still just one thread for our JavaScript program to run.
这里唯一不同于你写过的任何东西的魔法
The only magic that's different here than anything else you've ever written
从第6行到第11行出现了神奇的局部阻挡。
is the fact that line 6 through 11 get to magically locally block.
我们以前在语法上从来没有这种能力。
We never had that capability syntactically before.
现在我们有了一种隐藏的句法方式
And now we have a syntactic way of hiding away
状态机的所有复杂性，异步状态机。
all of the complexity of a state machine, an asynchronous state machine.
所以我们的代码看起来又是同步的。
So our code looks synchronous again.
不仅我们的常规代码看起来是同步的，
And not only does our regular code looks synchronous,
我们的错误处理再次变得同步。
our error handling becomes synchronous again.
我们如何进行同步错误处理，我们使用什么？
How do we do synchronous error handling, what do we use?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：尝试，接住。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Try, catch.
你可以绕着第6行尝试接球。
You can wrap try catch around line 6.
如果Ajax在幕后抛出了一些错误，
And if the AJAX under the covers threw some error,
该错误将立即返回并作为同步错误被捕获。
that error is gonna come right back in and get caught as a synchronous error.
因为在发电机内部，一切都恢复正常，同步，
Because inside of the generator, everything's back to normal, synchronous,
阻塞语义，包括错误处理。
blocking semantics including error handling.
因此我们得到了一个异步堆栈，该堆栈被规范化回
So we get an asynchronous stack that gets normalized back into
生成器内部的同步堆栈。
a synchronous stack inside of our generator.
是啊。
Yeah.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：线路11，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Line 11,
console.log(应答)-&gt；&gt；扬声器2：SO
console.log(answer)- &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: So
日志记录一直等到x加1被计算出来吗？
the logging wait until x plus 1 is computed?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：在第8行结束之前，第11行不会运行。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Line 11 doesn't run until after line 8 is finished.
在第6行结束之前，第7行不会运行。
Line 7 doesn't run until after line 6 is finished.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：因为这个关键字。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Because of that yield keyword.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：但是如果我有线路12，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: But if I have line 12,
这是console.log其他东西，它会被打印出来。
that's console.log something else, that would be printed.
&GT；&GT；凯尔·辛普森：那么它马上就会去。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Then it's gonna go right away.
我们只会在YORD关键字处暂停。
We only pause at the yield keyword.
其他所有内容都会一直运行，直到下一个YELD关键字为止。
Everything else keeps running until the next yield keyword.
或者直到结束然后它就结束了。
Or until the end and then it finishes.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 3：从技术上讲，第8行，你不需要在那里做让步
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Technically, line 8, you don't need to do a yield there
因为你在概念上真的没有拿到任何东西，对吧？
because you're really not conceptually fetching anything, right?
那只是计算本地的东西。
That's just computing something local.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：在我们所有运行意义的生命例子中，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: In all of our running meaning of life example,
我们总是将这三个电话都具体化。
we always externalized all three calls.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：好的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Okay.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：所以我也在做同样的事情。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So I'm doing the exact same thing.
我们假装那根绳子需要送到某个地方
We're pretending as if that string needs to get sent off somewhere and
本地化成我们自己的外星人语言或者别的什么。
localized into our own alien language or whatever.
然后它就会回到我们身边，好吧。
And then it comes back to us, okay.
怎么了？
Yes?
&GT；&GT；扬声器4：他们再次问，在第16行，他们是否在那里运行，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: They're asking again, on line 16, if they had put a run there,
调用setTimeout后会执行吗？
Would that execute after calling setTimeout?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：如果在第16行，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: If on line 16 you put a run there,
它会恢复等待的发电机
it would resume the generator that's waiting on
第6行，而不是向它发送一个值。
line 6 right away, not sending it a value.
并且当setTimeout试图运行调用运行时，
And when the setTimeout tried to run call run,
如果生成器当前未处于暂停状态，则会产生错误。
if the generator was not in a currently paused state, that would create an error.
所以你不想让很多不同的人尝试恢复你的
So you do not want to try to have lots of different people trying to resume your
发电机在很多不同的地方。
generator in lots of different places.
这真是个糟糕的主意。
That's a really terrible idea.
发电机只能
The generator can only,
在任何给定的时间，JavaScript中只能发生一件事。
only one thing can ever be happening in JavaScript at any given time.
所以我们没有这个问题。
So we don't have that problem.
但你不想用那个迭代器。下一步和
But you don't want to take that iterator.next and
有很多不同的人叫它，因为你会弄乱顺序。
have lots of different people calling it, cuz you'll get out of sequence.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：我在这里看到一个关于在生成器中使用承诺的问题。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: I see a question in here about using promises in the generator.
坚持住，我们会到的。
Hold on, we'll get there.
我保证我们就快到了。
I promise, we're almost there.
&GT；&GT；凯尔·辛普森：我只是想让这一刻沉浸在其中。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: I just wanna let a moment for this to sink in.
因为这就像是神圣的垃圾时刻。
Cuz this is like that holy crap moment.
就像，哇，我可以做同步看起来异步编程？
Like, whoa, I get to do synchronous looking asynchronous programming?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：我之前看到一些人问这个有哪些用例。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: I saw some people asking earlier what are some use cases of this.
我第一次看到这个是五或者
The very first time I saw this was five or
六年前，标准中还没有发电机。
six years ago before there were generators in the standard.
Firefox将生成器放入他们的
Firefox put generators into their
JavaScript引擎的实现大约在十年前。
implementation of JavaScript engine about a decade ago.
我在Firefox的开发者工具团队工作。
And I was working at Firefox on the developer tools team.
每次我们向开发人员工具添加功能时，
And every time we would add a feature to a developer tool,
当然，我们需要一个测试用例，一些特性的测试套件。
of course we needed a test case for it, a test suite for some feature.
以及您在Firefox浏览器中使用JavaScript所做的一切，
And everything you do in the Firefox browser that you're doing in JavaScript,
都是异步的。
it's all asynchronous.
没有同步的东西，每个API都是异步的。
There's no synchronous anything, every single API is asynchronous.
嗯，写异步测试用例真的，真的很难。
Well, it gets really, really hard to write asynchronous test cases.
当每一个人都喜欢画边界，然后等待它发生。
When every single like draw border and then wait for that to happen.
真正的问题是这些调用没有一个，我是说，它们都是异步的。
And the real problem is that none of those calls, I mean, they're all asynchronous.
但是没有一个事件可以让你知道他们已经结束了。
But none of them have events to let you know that they finished.
所以你真的就像做setTimeout，我是说，这很疯狂，
So you literally are just like doing setTimeout, I mean, it was crazy,
在那种环境下编写测试用例很糟糕。
terrible to write test cases in that environment.
因为它是异步的，没有任何步骤已经完成的通知。
Because it was asynchronicity without any notification that the step had completed.
所以你可以想象我的测试用例是可怕的。
So you can imagine that my test cases were horrible.
然后有一天我的一个同事说
And then one day one of my coworkers was like well,
你为什么不直接用发电机重写呢？
why don't you just rewrite all with a generator?
我说什么？
And I was like what?
我开始通读，我想，我的上帝。
And I started reading through and I was like, my God.
我可以同步的方式编写测试用例
I can write my test cases in a synchronous fashion and
让所有的异步垃圾，所有的超时和东西，隐藏起来？
let all that asynchronicity crap, all the timeouts and stuff, hide that away?
它改变了一切。
It changed everything.
&GT；&GT；凯尔·辛普森：我在我们获得着陆希望的几年前就看到了这一点
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: I saw that years before we ever got a hope of that landing as part
JavaScript标准的。
of the JavaScript standard.
但我一直是你的超级粉丝
But I've been a big fan for
很长一段时间，因为同步看起来异步是那颗神奇的银弹。
a long time because synchronous looking async is that magical silver bullet.
在编程语言设计中，你不会经常遇到这些问题。
And you don't get those very often in programming language design.
那些神奇的银子弹不知从哪里冒出来。
Those magical silver bullets that come out of nowhere.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：所以当我前面说承诺是伟大的，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So when I said earlier that promises are great and
承诺链为我们提供了一些流控制。
promise chains give us some flow control.
但是，我甚至说我做了异步图书馆
But, and I even said that I did the asynquence library and
给了我自己的序列。
gave me self sequences.
然后我说，实际上，我不再用那些了，这就是为什么。
And then I said that actually, I don't use those anymore, this is why.
因为我在生成器中编写了100%的异步代码。
Cuz I write a 100% of my asynchronous code inside of generators.
如果您可以选择写入同步外观异步，
If you have the option of writing synchronous looking async,
你到底为什么要再写一次诺言链？
why on earth would you ever want to write a promise chain again?
我不知道，我想不出一个单独的案例为什么承诺链
I don't know, I can't come up with a single case why a promise chain would
当我有这个选择的时候，永远不会成为我想写的东西。
ever be what I wanna write, when I have that option.
所以我回去了，完全改变了我的整个思维方式。
So I've gone back and completely rechanged my whole way of thinking.
一旦我了解了发电机的力量，我就回去
Once I got to understanding the power of generators, I've gone back and
完全改变了我的思维方式。
completely changed my way of thinking.
现在我要做的就是把所有东西都放进发电机里。
And now what I do is put everything inside of a generator.